# Sunita Gajurel

sg78@uw.edu FederalWay,Washington (+1 4254695801) https://github.com/sunitagajurel https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunitagajurel

Passionate CS graduate with experience in software development and data analytics committed to utilizing the latest technologies to tackle intricate issues and improve user interactions. With a strong foundation in software engineering principles and a steadfast dedication to continuous learning, I am determined to contribute my expertise to drive the success of forward-thinking projects.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, C, C++, SQl, Bash, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript,

**Technologies:** React, Next,Node.js, Django, Linux, Git,Docker,Cloud Computing(AWS,Azure,GCP),Serverless Computing,Web development, Front End DevelopmentMessaging services (Rabbit MQ, Kafka),Object-Oriented-Development.,Data Structures And Algorithms,Devops,Docker,Big Data,Map Reduce.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Washington(Expected Graduation: Dec 2023)

Masters in Computer Science and Systems (GPA:3.9)

(2022-Present)

Tribhuvan University(Kathmandu, Nepal)

Bachelors in Computer Engineering (GPA:3.6)

2015-2019

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Engineer I**

Cotiviti Inc.

01/2020-08/2021

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Designed and implemented manual and automated test suites using CypressJs and led to multiple successful production releases.

## **Software Developer Intern**

09/2019-12/2019

Truemark Pvt Ltd

Developed a production-ready trivia Quiz application using React-native and collaborated with 5+ team members on a web application using React JS.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Messaging Services for Serverless Computing: An Investigation of Performance and Vendor Lock-in (Python, RabbitMQ, Kafka) (Individual MS Capstone Project)

Compares the performance(message and data throughput) of different cloud-based messaging services for serverless platforms and investigates vendor-lock-in issues in them.

### House Price Prediction (Machine Learning, Linear regression, Python) (Individual BigData Project)

Predicted the house price based on different features using Linear Regression and XGBoost Regression after cleaning and transforming the data.

#### Vehicle Renting Android Application (ReactNative, Firebase, Google Maps API) (Group Project)

Android app using react- native, firebase real time database and firebase function that allows people to provide their private vehicle on rent and see the real time location of the rentee.

# Employee Monitoring and Attendance System(Node-Red, Java Script, Raspberry PI, Grafana) (Group IOT Project)

Image Recognition based attendance system, Employee monitoring system, automated lighting as well as automated emergency and weather alert using Node-Red, JavaScript and Raspberry PI.